A Guide to the Cocke and Related Family Papers
University of Virginia Library
- SERIES III: GENEALOGICAL & HISTORICAL RESEARCH FILES OF JOHN PAGE Elliot
  - Bowdoin Family- Notes, Transcripts, and Printed Material, ca. 1960-1991 (Box Box 27)
  - Bowdoin Family- Wills & Inventories (Copies), [1736-1775] (Box Box 27)
  - " Bremo, " Fluvanna County, Virginia- Auction Sale of Property from the Estates of Mary B. Cocke and Lelia B. Cocke, 1926; (2 folders) (Box Box 27)
  - " Bremo, " Fluvanna County, Virginia- Correspondence re " Bremo", 1926-1988 (Box Box 27)
  - " Bremo, " Fluvanna County, Virginia- Library List of Books at " Bremo" and Other Articles, 1935, 1958, n.d. (Box Box 27)
  - " Bremo, " Fluvanna County, Virginia- Newsclippings and Printed Material, ca. 1931-1988 (Box Box 27)
  - " Bremo, " Fluvanna County, Virginia- Photographs, 1923, n.d. (Box Box 27)
  - Browne Family, " Four Mile Tree Plantation, " Surry County- Correspondence re and Printed Material, ca. 1940-1988, n.d. (Box Box 28)
  - Browne Family, " Four Mile Tree Plantation, " Surry County- Notes and Photographs (Box Box 28)
  - Burwell Family, ca. 1940-1992 (Box Box 28)
  - Byrd Family- Printed Material, 1962 & 1966 (Box Box 28)
  - Calvert Family, 1948-1966, n.d. (Box Box 28)
  - Carroll Family, ca. 1955-1975, n.d. (Box Box 28)
  - Carter Family- Newsclippings, ca. 1948-1987, n.d. (Box Box 28)
  - Carter Family- Notes, etc., ca. 1937-1942, n.d. (Box Box 28)
  - Carter Family- Printed Material, 1958-1991, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 28)
  - Betty Page Cocke(1872-1973), ca. 1905-1980 (Box Box 29)
  - Betty Page Cocke- Photographs, ca. 1896-1973; (2 folders) (Box Box 29)
  - Betty Page Cocke- Robert E. Lee Memorial Foundation, 1926-1936, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 29)
  - Betty Cocke Scholarship Fund, 1973-1976 (Box Box 29)
  - John Bowdoin Cocke(1836-1889), 1858-1992 (Box Box 29)
  - John Bowdoin Cocke- Mechanical & Architectural Drawings for a class at the Virginia Military Institute, 1854-1855 (Box Box 29)
  - John T. Bowdoin Cocke(1871-1951), 1888-1934 (Box Box 29)
  - General John H. Cocke(1780-1866) - Correspondence re, Notes, etc., ca. 1933-1988 (Box Box 30)
  - General John H. Cocke- Diary, from November 6, 1816 to May 19, 1818, " Bremo, " Fluvanna County(Copy), n.d. (Box Box 30)
  - General John H. Cocke- Financial Records (Copies), [1797-1863] (Box Box 30)
  - General John H. Cocke- Photographs, n.d. (Box Box 30)
  - General John H. Cocke- Printed Material & Newsclippings, 1921-1983 (Box Box 30)
  - Mary Louise Cocke(1868-1966) - Photographs, n.d. (Box Box 30)
  - Norborne Page Cocke(1878-1940), 1895-1968 (Box Box 30)
  - General Philip St. George Cocke- Correspondence re, 1932-1992, n.d. (Box Box 30)
  - General Philip St. George Cocke- Correspondence from Douglas Southall Freeman re General Cocke, 1930-1938 (Box Box 30)
  - General Philip St. George Cocke- Printed Material, Photographs, & Notes, 1902-1992 (Box Box 30)
  - Richard Cocke I (1615-1665) and Descendants - Correspondence re, 1930-1992; (2 folders) (Box Box 31)
  - Richard Cocke I and Descendants - Notes, 1895, n.d. (Box Box 31)
  - Richard Cocke I and Descendants - Printed Material and Photographs, 1929-1988, n.d. (Box Box 31)
  - Cocke Family- Deed, including Copies, Transcripts, and Correspondence re Deeds, 1987, n.d. (Box Box 31)
  - Cocke Family- "A Game Cock Breed Book from Virginia: 1787-1798" by Richard E. Powell, Jr., 1988 (Box Box 31)
  - Cocke Family- Miscellaneous Notes, n.d. (Box Box 31)
  - Cocke Family- Miscellaneous Printed, Newsclippings, & Copies, [1870]-1989 (Box Box 31)
  - Cocke Family- Poetry Manuscripts & Recipes, 1810-1822, 1832-1834, n.d. (Box Box 32)
  - Cocke Family- Related Families, n.d. (Box Box 32)
  - Cocke Family- Wills, including Copies, Transcripts, & Correspondence re Wills, 1987-1990, n.d. (Box Box 32)
  - Corbin Family, 1951-1988 (Box Box 32)
  - Curle Family, n.d. (Box Box 32)
  - Napoleon Bonaparte Drew- Photographs, [ante 1924 ?] (Box Box 32)
  - Drew Family, n.d. (Box Box 32)
  - Allmand Elliot(1881-1908), 1899-1984 (Box Box 32)
  - Charles Elliot(1877-1938), 1901-1988 (Box Box 32)
  - Elizabeth Preston (Elliot) Wilson(1887- ?), 1909, n.d. (Box Box 32)
  - George Blow Elliot(1873-1948), 1922-1981 (Box Box 32)
  - Gilbert Elliot(1843-1895) - The Albemarle, 1928-1980 (Box Box 32)
  - Gilbert Elliot I-IV - Notes, n.d. (Box Box 32)
  - Gilbert Elliot I-IV - Photographs, Printed Material & Correspondence, 1927-1987, n.d. (Box Box 33)
  - Lucy Hamilton Cocke Elliot, 1895-1983, n.d. (Box Box 33)
  - Lucy Hamilton Cocke Elliot- Photographs, n.d. (Box Box 33)
  - Margaret Elliot(1884-1966), ca. 1963-1967, n.d. (Box Box 33)
  - Milton C. Elliot- A Century of Elliots based on the diary of Charles Grice Elliot(1840-1901), 1908 (Box Box 33)
  - Milton C. Elliot(1879-1928) - Correspondence re and Notes, etc., 1880-1984 (Box Box 33)
  - Milton C. Elliot- Federal Reserve Board, 1914-1927, n.d. (Box Box 33)
  - Milton C. Elliot- Photographs, ca. 1895-1928 (Box Box 33)
  - Milton C. Elliot- Printed Material, 1902-1950 (Box Box 33)
  - Robert Garrison Elliot- The Elliots from Norfolk County, Virginia, to Camden and Pasquotank Counties, North Carolina (Box Box 34)
  - Warren Grice Elliot(1848-1906), 1896, 1957-1976, n.d. (Box Box 34)
  - Warren Grice Elliot, Jr.(1875-1930), ca. 1923-1986, n.d. (Box Box 34)
  - Warren Grice Elliot, Jr.- Photographs, ca. 1891-1911, n.d. (Box Box 34)
  - Elliot Clan Society, 1976-1989 (Box Box 34)
  - Elliot Family- Miscellaneous, ca. 1928-1982, n.d. (Box Box 34)
  - Elliot Family- Unrelated, 1974-1982 (Box Box 34)
  - James Westhall Ford(1794-1866) - re his portrait of General John Hartwell Cocke, 1951, 1985, n.d. (Box Box 34)
  - " Four Acres, " Charlottesville, Virginia, 1980-1990, n.d. (Box Box 34)
  - " Four Mile Tree Plantation, " Surry County, 1936, 1979-1990, n.d. (Box Box 34)
  - Genealogical & Historical Correspondence of the Cocke Family, 1904-1968 (Box Box 34)
  - Genealogical & Historical Correspondence of John Page Elliot, 1936-1992, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 35)
  - Genealogical & Historical Correspondence of John Page Elliot re the Elliot Family, 1958-1987 (Box Box 35)
  - Charles Grice(1763-1833) - The Little Charles, ca. 1923-1986, n.d. (Box Box 35)
  - Grice Family- Correspondence, Printed Material, Photographs & Notes of [Susan Charles] Grice, 1928-1989 (Box Box 35)
  - Grice Family- Notes & Charts, n.d. (Box Box 35)
  - Hall, Hansford, Harrison, Kennon, Mann, and Mason Families, 1941-1991, n.d. (Box Box 35)
  - Hartwell Family, 1933-1974, n.d. (Box Box 35)
  - Harmanson Family, 1975, n.d. (Box Box 36)
  - Hill Family- Notes, Printed Material & Correspondence re, 1908-1965, n.d. (Box Box 36)
  - Hill Family- Notes & Photographs, n.d. (Box Box 36)
  - Historic Homes, 1932-1980 (Box Box 36)
  - Huguenot Society of America, 1978-1979 (Box Box 36)
  - Jones Family, 1929-1953, n.d. (Box Box 36)
  - Kennon Family, n.d. (Box Box 36)
  - Lee Family, 1928-1977 (Box Box 36)
  - " Lower Bremo" and " Bremo Recess, " Fluvanna County, Virginia, 1935-1988 (Box Box 36)
  - " Malvern Hill, " Henrico County, n.d. (Box Box 36)
  - " Mount Pleasant, " Surry County- Correspondence re and Photographs, 1973-1990, n.d. (Box Box 36)
  - " Mount Pleasant, " Surry County- Notes, Printed Material, etc., 1929-1933, n.d. (Box Box 36)
  - Nelson Family- Correspondence, Photographs, & Notes, 1896, 1948-1991 (Box Box 36)
  - Nelson Family- Printed Material, 1932-1989, n.d. (Box Box 36)
  - Newsclippings, ca. 1958-1990, n.d. (Box Box 37)
  - " Old Bremo, " Curles Neck, Henrico County, Virginia, 1933-1936 (Box Box 37)
  - Page Family- Correspondence re and Notes, 1865, 1903-1980, n.d. (Box Box 37)
  - Page Family- Photographs, n.d. (Box Box 37)
  - Page Family- Printed Material, ca. 1927-1986, n.d. (Box Box 37)
  - Photographs - Miscellaneous, 1903-1904, n.d. (Box Box 37)
  - Pocahontas, John Rolfe, and the Powhatan Indians, 1925-1992, n.d. (Box Box 37)
  - Preeson Family, 1985, n.d. (Box Box 37)
  - Randolph Family, 1966-1993 (Box Box 37)
  - Ruffin Family, ca. 1950-1990, n.d. (Box Box 37)
  - Skipwith Family, 1988, n.d. (Box Box 37)
  - Swann Family, 1986, n.d. (Box Box 37)
  - " Swann's Point Plantation, " Surry County, Virginia, 1933-1986, n.d. (Box Box 38)
  - Tayloe Family, 1956-1985, n.d. (Box Box 38)
  - Thoroughgood Family, 1965-1975, n.d. (Box Box 38)
  - Edward Troye(1808-1874) - Correspondence re his Paintings, 1926-1990; (2 folders) (Box Box 38)
  - Edward Troye(1808-1874) - Copies of Original Correspondence re the Horses belonging to the Cocke Family and Their Portraits, 1800-1874 (Box Box 38)
  - Edward Troye(1808-1874) - Printed Material and Photographs, 1938-1981, n.d. (Box Box 38)
  - Tucker Family, 1957-1987 (Box Box 38)
  - Waller Family, ca. 1951-1987, n.d. (Box Box 38)
  - William & Mary- P.D.A. Society Medal & Phi Beta Kappa, 1936-1982 (Box Box 38)
  - Yorktown Map, 1955-1991, n.d. (Box Box 38)
- SERIES IV: BOUND VOLUMES, MEMORABILIA, & OVERSIZE MATERIAL
  - Memorabilia, 1893-1962, n.d. (Box Box 39)
  - Episcopal High School of Virginia Annual belonging to Fontaine Alger Cocke, Columbus, Mississippi, with some University of Virginia Class Notes, ca. 1895-1900 (Box Box 39)
  - Notebook of Essays by Betty Burwell (Page) Cocke and other Cocke Family Members, 1859-1884 (Box Box 39)
  - School Notebook belonging to John Bowdoin Cocke, ca. 1854 (Box Box 39)
  - School Notebooks belonging to Lucy Hamilton Cocke, 1893-1894 (Box Box 39)
  - 1) University of Virginia Autograph Book belonging to John Bowdoin Cocke, 1856-1857 (Box Box 39)
  - 2) School Notebook belonging to Lelia B. Cocke, " Bremo, " Fluvanna County, 1867 Oct 12 (Box Box 39)
  - 3) School Notebook belonging to [L. Eliza ?] Browne, ca. 1813 (Box Box 39)
  - 4-5) Travel Journals of a Trip to Europe by John Bowdoin Cocke, 1858; (2 volumes) (Box Box 40)
  - 6) Memoranda Book belonging to Betty B. Cocke, with notes re a trip to New York, 1873-1882 (Box Box 40)
  - 7) Address Book of Miss Betty Page Cocke, n.d. (Box Box 40)
  - 8) Scrapbook of clippings, n.d. (Box Box 40)
  - 9) Diary belonging to Lucy H. Cocke, 1895 (Box Box 40)
  - 10) Twixt Cupid & Croesus by Charles P. Didier, belonging to Lucy H. Cocke, 1896 (Box Box 40)
  - 11) Diary belonging to Lucy H. Cocke, 1903 (Box Box 40)
  - 12) List of Wedding Invitations kept by Lucy H. Cocke, 1906 Aug (Box Box 40)
  - 13) Visiting List Book belonging to Lucy Cocke Elliot, Washington, D.C., 1914-1916 (Box Box 40)
  - 14) Private Account Book of M.C. Elliot, ca. 1900-[1901?] (Box Box 40)
  - 15) Ledger with Index, belonging to M.C. Elliot, 1919-1924 (Box Box 40)
  - 16) Diary of Milton C. Elliot, 1928 (Box Box 40)
  - 17) Address Book of M.C. Elliot, n.d. (Box Box 40)
  - 18) Memoranda Book of M.C. Elliot (Box Box 40)
  - 19) Notebook containing a collection of 107 dialect sayings, n.d. (Box Box 40)
  - 20) Photograph Album of University of Virginia scenes belonging to Lucy H. Cocke, [pre 1906?] (Box Box 41)
  - Bag constructed from University of Virginia ribbons from Eli Banana, German Club, O.N.E., Omega Sigma, and T.I.L.K.A., ca. 1893-1895 (Box Mini-tray 40)
  - Keepsake Box belonging to [Miss Betty P. Cocke?], n.d. (Box Mini-tray 40)
  - Various University of Virginia ribbons from T.I.L.K.A., Z Society, Final Ball, Eli Banana, Omega Sigma Finals, German Club, Beta Theta Pi Fraternity Annual German, and the O.F.C. Club; 27th District Convention Delegate ribbon; and the Ladies Cotillon, 1893-1899, 1933 (Box Mini-tray 40)
  - University of Virginia pins, including Eli Banana pins, Thirteen Club pin, T.I.L.K.A. pins & a belt buckle; the Yorktown Sesquicentennial Commission Medal; and the 3rd Pan-American Commercial Conference Medal, 1931, n.d. (Box Mini-tray 40)
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL
  - Pardon & Amnesty from Andrew Johnson to John Bowdoin Cocke, 1865 Jul 6 (Box Folder 1 (OS Box P-16))
  - Architectural Drawings for a "Residence to be erected for Milton C. Elliot" near Charlottesville, Virginia, by Eugene Bradbury, n.d.; (5 sheets) (Box Folder 1 (OS Box P-16))
  - Photographs of Dr. Norborne Page Cocke, n.d.; (3 photos) (Box Folder 1 (OS Box P-16))
  - Photograph of George Blow Elliot, 1910 (Box Folder 1 (OS Box P-16))
  - Photograph of William Gibbs McAdoo, 1918 Nov (Box Folder 1 (OS Box P-16))
  - Group Photograph of W.G. McAdoo, John Skelton Williams and others (Box Folder 1 (OS Box P-16))
  - Certificate of Appointment of M.C. Elliot to Treasury Department, Comptroller of Currency to examine the affairs of National Banking Associations, 1908 Jan 9 (Box Folder 1 (OS Box P-16))
  - Legal Certificates of M.C. Elliot to Practice Law in the Orphan's Court for the County of Philadelphia; the Court of Common Pleas, First Judicial District of Pennsylvania; Attorney and Counsellor of the Supreme Court of Pennsylvania; and the U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals for the Fifth Circuit, 1909-1926 (Box Folder 1 (OS Box P-16))
  - Membership Certificates of M.C. Elliot to the Ancient Arabic Order of the Nobles of the Mystic Shrine and to the University Club of Washington, 1915 & 1923 (Box Folder 1 (OS Box P-16))
  - Passport of Mary Louise Cocke, 1915 (Box Folder 1 (OS Box P-16))
  - Legal Certificates of M.C. Elliot to practice law as Attorney and Counsellor of the Supreme Court of the United States; the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia; Attorney and Counsellor of Law in Virginia; and the Court of Appeals of the District of Columbia, 1902-1925 (Box Folder 2 (OS Box M-19))
  - Photograph of the Federal Reserve Board, with M.C. Elliot as the first General Counsel of the Board, n.d. (Box Folder 2 (OS Box M-19))
  - University of Virginia Law School Centennial Anniversary Certificate, 1921 Apr 4 (Box Folder 2 (OS Box M-19))
  - Certificate of Appreciation to M.C. Elliot from the Almas Temple Ancient Arabic Order of the Nobles of the Mystic Shrine, 1923 Jun 5-7 (Box Folder 2 (OS Box M-19))
  - Architectural Drawing of a Stable by Eugene Bradbury for M.C. Elliot, n.d. (Box Folder 2 (OS Box M-19))
  - Photostatic Copies of Cocke Family Indentures and R.C.M. Page's Genealogy (Box Folder 2 (OS Box M-19))
  - John Tucker Bowdoin Cocke Certificate of Membership in the Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, 1926 Jun 1 (Box Folder 3 (OS Tray 55))
  - Architectural Drawings by Johnson, Craven & Gibson for a House for Mr. & Mrs. John P. Elliot, " Belle Rive, " Fairfax County, 1969 Jul 15; (3 sets, 24 sheets) (Box Folder 3 (OS Tray 55))
  - Architectural Drawings by James S. Tuley, of Alterations & Additions to the Residence of Mr. & Mrs. John Page Elliot, 1108 Hilltop Road, Charlottesville, Virginia, 1973 Sep 24; (1 sheet) (Box Folder 3 (OS Tray 55))
  - Genealogical Chart of John Page Elliot's ancestors, n.d. (Box Folder 4 (OS Tray 34))
  - Architectural Drawings by Johnson, Craven, & Gibson for a Garden House, Mr. & Mrs. John P. Elliot, 1117 Prince Street, Alexandria, Virginia, 1960 Jul 1; (3 sets, 6 sheets) (Box Folder 4 (OS Tray 34))
  - Architectural Drawings by Eugene Bradbury for a Residence for Milton C. Elliot to be built on Massachusetts Avenue, Washington, D.C., 1925 Jul; (18 sheets) (Box Folder 4 (OS Tray 34))
  - Architectural Drawings by Marshall S. Wells of a Residence for Mrs. M.C. Elliot, Charlottesville, Virginia, 1940 Jan 12; (11 sheets) (Box Folder 4 (OS Tray 34))
  - Architectural Drawings by Johnson, Craven, & Gibson for Details for a Doorway and Steps on a Doorway at 1117 Prince Street, Alexandria, Virginia, 1959-1960; (4 sheets) (Box Folder 4 (OS Tray 34))